Ibragim Zubailov

@ karlson.zim@gmail.com | in LinkedIn | Telegram | Github | Portfolio | Montenegro

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm a Backend Engineer with experience in Node.js, Go, Databases, Teamlead, Techlead

Experience with highload projects (up to 500k rps), and projects with a large number of users (up to 1 million) Also I have experience in building teams, hiring, and mentoring, and I'm ready to share my experience with you

SKILLS

Programming: Go, TypeScript, Node.js, NestJS, Web3(Blockchain), PHP

Storage: Clickhouse, Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Aerospike Transport: Kafka, RabbitMQ, NATS, GRPC, GraphQL, Websockets

Others: GlusterFS, ElasticSearch, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Nginx, Prometheus, Grafana

Languages: Russian (native), English (intermediate)

WORK EXPERIENCE (6 YEARS)

MTS Group

Moscow, Russia

Senior Go and Node.js Developer

 $Jun 2022 - Jun 2023 \cdot Remote (1y.)$

- Identified a balance issue between storage systems and developed a service to optimize load handling.
- Eliminated a bottleneck in data retrieval from storage, increasing performance 10x.

• Analyzed data to pinpoint key growth areas for advertising arbitrage (OpenRTB).

• Facilitated team operations by creating tools for workflow simplification, which enhanced overall team productivity.

Lofty Topmload (8 BACKEND DEVELOPERS)

Moscow, Russia

 $May 2020 - May 2022 \cdot Hybrid (2y.)$

- Teamlead (8 BACKEND DEVELOPERS)
 - Streamlined team processes: incorporated **KPIs**, a roadmap, an idea board, task decomposition.
 - Devised a traffic quality forecasting system to optimize costs and filtering for SSP.
 - Conceived and developed a system for assessment and filtration (Antifraud), ensuring quality for DSP.
 - Boosted the annual profit of a project from 0 to 1 million USD within two years, in high-load product with under 500k rps.

Techlead (4 BACKEND DEVELOPERS)

Oct 2019 — May 2020 · On-site (8m.)

- Overhauled an application to achieve stability, 3x performance, and A/B testing capability, which enabled performance enhancement from 15k to 150k RPS over two years.
- Implemented Agile, optimized hiring and staff adaptation processes.
- Contributed to architectural design and DevOps, enhancing data storage efficiency.

Senior Node.js Developer

Jul 2019 — Oct 2019 · On-site (4m.)

- Developed a high-load (70k rps) service for sending push notifications with extensive customization options.
- Created a microservice for authorization.

Belsona Investment Group Node.js Developer

Moscow, Russia

Jun 2017 — Jul 2019 · On-site (2y.)

- Engineered a bot for arbitrage between **blockchain smart contracts** and exchanges (**Binance/Bitfinex**).
- Created a risk assessment and predictive market trend model based on blockchain data.
- Implemented automated scripts to reduce routine tasks, particularly for ICO projects.
- Developed a service for calculating risks of ICO products.

EDUCATION